{
    "id": "65fe8808c39b48b186082a0623cb168e",
    "title": "Ing Forms Or To-Infinitives",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6b8c4d69a164482fac2fffd9cd387eda",
            "title": "Ing Form Or To Infinitive",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The thought ………………………… never entered his head.",
                    "description": "The noun thought is followed by of + ing form. The infinitive is not possible in this case.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to fail",
                        "of failing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She is quite good ………………………. puzzles.",
                    "description": "The adjective good is followed by at + ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to solve",
                        "at solving",
                        "in solving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am tired ………………………. to your advice.",
                    "description": "The adjective tired is followed by of + ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to listen",
                        "of listening",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can’t talk without ………………………. your mouth.",
                    "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "opening",
                        "to open",
                        "open"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We managed to finish the job by ……………………….. over time.",
                    "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "work",
                        "working",
                        "to work"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We repaired the roof instead of …………………………. on vacation.",
                    "description": "When we put a verb after a preposition, it is usually in the ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "go",
                        "to go",
                        "going"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I look forward to ……………………….. a grandmother.",
                    "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘look forward to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "become",
                        "becoming",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am not used to ………………………… in big cities.",
                    "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘be used to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "live",
                        "living",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He objects to ……………………… on weekends.",
                    "description": "The ‘to’ in the expression ‘object to’ is a preposition. We use an ing form after a preposition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "working",
                        "work"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "They don’t permit ………………………… in the conference hall.",
                    "description": "When there is no object, we use an ing form after permit.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to smoke",
                        "smoking",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We regret ………………………. you that the flight has been cancelled.",
                    "description": "Regret is followed by an infinitive in announcements of bad news.",
                    "answers": [
                        "informing",
                        "to inform",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The principal has forbidden students ……………………….. in the corridors.",
                    "description": "When there is an object, we use an infinitive after forbid.",
                    "answers": [
                        "sing",
                        "to sing",
                        "singing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}